电视∶他正向篮筐奔跑,2秒,他跳起来了,进了!
TV: He drives for the basket, two seconds, he's up, it's good!
迈克杰森和本∶(欢呼)
Mike Jason and Ben: (cheering)
电视∶比分打成平局!我们进入加时赛!
TV: And the Knicks tie it up!We go into overtime!
杰森∶好样的!
Jason: Alright here we go!
麦琪∶杰森!克莉丝和我在车里都等累了.
Maggie: Jason!Chrissy and I are getting tired of waiting out in the car.
你说过三十秒内比赛就要结束的.
You said the game would be over in thirty seconds.
杰森∶好消息,亲爱的,
Jason: Great news, honey, the Knicks just tied it up,
比分打平了,还有加时赛呢!
we're heading into overtime!
麦琪∶不,我们不想等了,我们要送克莉丝去托儿所了.
Maggie: No, we're not.We're going to Chrissy's playschool.
杰森∶放松,放松,外面不会有交通堵塞的.只要是美国人,都在看这个比赛.
Jason: Hon...honey, hey, relax, relax, there's not gonna be any traffic out there.Everybody
who calls himself an American is watching this game
麦琪∶杰森!什么更重要,
Maggie: Jason!What's more important here,
是愚蠢的比赛还是克莉丝上学的第一天?
this silly game or Chrissy's first day at school?
杰森∶我刚才有提到加时吗?我来了,
Jason: Hey, hey, hey, did I mention it was overtime?
我来了,我来了.
I'm coming, I'm coming, I'm coming.
开萝尔∶还好,你们还在这里.
Carol: Good, you guys are still here.
给你克莉丝,
Here Chrissy, it's my old animal pencil case,
这是我的旧的动物铅笔盒,还有大象橡皮和斑马卷笔刀.
with the elephant eraser and the zebra sharpener.
麦琪∶哦,你真是太懂事了,不是...亲爱的!
Maggie: Oh, it's so sweet of you, isn't it hon...Honey!
杰森∶好了,好了,正在穿外套.
Jason: Yep, yep, yep.Just putting on my coat.
麦琪∶你已经穿了外套.
Maggie: You're wearing your coat.
杰森∶我们还有几分钟.
Jason: OK, then we have a couple more minutes.
迈克∶爸爸,我的学前班的第一天,你有带我去吗?
Mike: Dad, did you take me to my first day at pre-school?
杰森∶是的,是的,因此而错过了世界锦标赛的第7场比赛.
Jason: Yeah, yeah.Missed the seventh game of the world series because of you.
本∶那我呢?
Ben: What about me?
杰森∶错过了里根-卡特的辩论.
Jason: Missed the Reagan-Carter debate.
所以这是我为什么一直最喜欢你的原因.
That's why you've always been my favourite.
麦琪∶杰森,如果你不想去..
Maggie: Look Jason if you don't wanna go...
杰森∶我想去!我来了!
Jason: I wanna go!I'm coming!I wanna go!
我想去!我一直在等开萝尔停止唠叨,这样我们就可以出发了.
I've been waiting for Carol to stop babbling here so we could hit the road.
开萝尔∶妈妈,爸爸,
Carol: Mom, Dad, I just think it's wonderful that you two are willing
在你们这样的年龄,仍然还愿意与克莉丝重新开始,真是太棒了.
to start all over again with Chrissy, at your age.
刚好昨天晚上欧波拉的节目中,有一段是讲家属与孩子的.
Just yesterday there was a segment on Operah, People with Kids.
教师∶所有人都准备好了牙刷吗?
Teacher: Is everybody ready for the toothbrush?
孩子们∶是的!
Kids: Yeah!
教师∶大家都来刷牙齿!准备,开始!
Teacher: Everybody brush your teeth!Ready, this is it!
上下,左右,大家都坐下!
Up and down, all around, everybody sit!
麦琪∶杰森,他们是如此年轻的.
Maggie: Jason, they're so young.
杰森∶当然年轻了,亲爱的,他们才2岁.
Jason: Course they're young, honey, they're two.
麦琪∶不是孩子们,是父母们.
Maggie: Not the kids, the parents.
麦琪∶哦,他们没有你说的那么年轻.
Jason: Oh, they're not all that young.
劳瑞∶劳驾,西维尔医生和西维尔太太,我是劳瑞卡特利吉,曾经和迈克约会过.
Laurie: Excuse me, Dr.and Mrs.Seaver, I'm Laurie McNeill, I used to date Mike.
杰森∶哦!劳瑞你好.
Jason: Oh, yeah, hi Laurie.
劳瑞∶你好.
Laurie: Hi.Hi.
麦琪∶你的宝宝真好看.
Maggie: Hi.And you have a beautiful baby.
劳瑞∶谢谢,他叫迦南.
Laurie: Thank you, this is Canaan.
麦琪∶你好迦南.
Maggie: Hi Canaan.
杰森∶啊,他也有和迈克一样的酒涡呢.
Jason: Yeah, look at that, he's got dimples just like Mike.
劳瑞∶那是有原因的.
Laurie: Yeah, there's a reason for that.
杰森∶哈?
Jason: Huh?
劳瑞∶他的爸爸也有像迈克一样的酒窝.
Laurie: His Daddy has dimples like Mike's too.
麦琪∶哦!他的爸爸也有!
Maggie: Oh, his Daddy does!
劳瑞∶是.
Laurie: Yes.
麦琪∶哦!
Maggie: Oh.
杰森∶哦!太好了!
Jason: Oh, that's wonderful.
劳瑞∶很高兴见到你们.
Laurie: It was nice seeing you guys.
杰森∶哦,真是受打击.
Jason: Oh, so that's what a stroke feels like.
教师∶你好,我是萨莉艾罗嘉纳,欢迎!
Teacher: Hi, I'm Sally Garner, welcome!
麦琪∶你好.麦琪和杰森西维尔,这是克莉丝.
Maggie: Hi, Maggie and Jason Seaver and this is Chrissy.
教师∶你好克莉丝,很高兴你能来我们班.
Teacher: Hi Chrissy, I am so glad you are in our class.
麦琪∶谢谢.
Maggie: Well thanks.
教师∶很多年轻的父母一定可以从你们的成熟经验中获益匪浅.
Teacher: You know all the young parents can certainly profit from your mature experience
麦琪∶成熟!对,我们还真的计划传达我们在第二次世界大战期间学到的东西.
Maggie: Mature!Well, we do plan to pass on so much of what we learned during world war two.
教师∶当真??
Teacher: Really?
杰森∶不,不,不,不,我的妻子只不过是开个小玩笑而已.
Jason: Na, na, na, na, I think my wife was just making a little joke there.
教师∶你使我想起了我的妈妈,她总是讲冷笑话.
Teacher: You remind me of my mom, she's always making jokes that nobody gets.
麦琪∶很荣幸.
Maggie: How nice.
教师∶来克莉丝!
Teacher: Come on Chrissy!
我要带你去见见一些新朋友.
I have some new friends over here that I want you to meet.
杰森∶麦琪,别当它是针对你而说的,她只是一个孩子.麦琪!
Jason: Come on Maggie, don't take it personally.She's just a kid.Maggie!
麦琪∶杰森,我们是这里最最老的父母.
Maggie: Jason, we're the oldest parents here.
杰森∶我们不是!你看那里也有我们一样年龄的家伙.哈罗,看上去很好玩.
Jason: We are not!Come on, there's a guy our age.Hello, that looks like fun.
男人∶是的,等等,宝贝儿.
Man: It sure is.Hang on, honey.
麦琪∶你女儿真的很可爱.
Maggie: Your daughter sure is adorable.
男人∶孙女.孙女.
Man: Granddaughter.Granddaughter.Yep,
我的孩子们让我帮他们带孩子.
my kids stuck Grandpa with babysitting duty again.
很显然的,你们也是一样.
But obviously you two know how that goes.
麦琪∶10点15分了,杰森,10点15分了.
Maggie: It's ten fifteen, Jason, ten fifteen.
杰森∶麦琪,别紧张,本只不过是迟到了15分钟的晚钟.
Jason: Maggie, easy, come on, Ben's only fifteen minutes late for his curfew.
麦琪∶经历了白天的事情后,我现在再也不想这样了!
Maggie: I don't need this after the day had!
杰森∶我们经历的事情和本迟到晚钟有什么关系?
Jason: What does the day we had have to do with Ben blowing curfew?
麦琪∶所有事物.杰森,
Maggie: Everything.Jason, do realise that we're going to be creaming kids
要记得我们还需要为这些跟孩子们说16年.
for missing curfews for at least another sixteen years.
到那时,我肯定头发都已经白了.
By then I'll look like one of the Golden Girls.
杰森∶麦琪,不要拿那个开玩笑.
Jason: Maggie, don't even joke about that.
麦琪∶我没有,杰森,
Maggie: I'm not, Jason,
你没有意识到当我们把克莉丝养大后,我会有多老了吗?
do you realise how old I'll be when we're going through this with Chrissy?
杰森∶是.比我再一岁.我们不应该生她的.
Jason: Yes.A year older than me.Bad time for that one.
迈克∶你好,我要出去一下,不要熬夜等我!
Mike: Hi guys, I'm not here, don't wait up!
杰森∶等等!你现在要出去?已经过了10点了!
Jason: Wait, wait, wait, you're going out now?Come on, it's after ten!
迈克∶好了爸爸,聚会直到至少1点或2点才好玩.
Mike: Come on, Dad, the party won't be going good till at least one or two.
麦琪∶迈克!
Maggie: Mike!
迈克∶别紧张!难道你们2个没有年轻过?
Mike: Guys, guys, lighten up!Weren't you two ever young?
麦琪∶我都回想不起来了.
Maggie: Not that I can recall.
迈克∶啊?我说什么了?
Mike: What'd I say?
杰森∶哦,哪壶不开提哪壶.
Jason: Oh, just the worst possible thing at the worst possible time.
迈克∶我并非有意的.
Mike: I didn't mean it.
杰森∶你有禀赋.出去吧,迈克.
Jason: You've got a gift.Get out, Mike.
迈克∶没问题.
Mike: You got it.
杰森∶宝贝儿,我觉得你反应太激烈了....
Jason: Honey, come on, I think you're over reacting...
有时我会觉得笨手笨脚本让我觉得很开心;这样,就很好管束他了.
You know sometimes I'm glad Ben is such a klutz; it makes him easier to catch.
麦琪∶不,让我来.我现在想要吃人呢.
Maggie: No, let me.I'm in the mood to chew somebody out.
杰森∶最好是他不要是我.
Jason: Better him than me.
麦琪∶本西维尔!站住!你不知道现在几点了吗?
Maggie: Ben Seaver!Freeze!Do you happen to know what time it is, young man?
本∶我的手表现实8点半.晚安.
Ben: My watch says eight thirty.Good night.
麦琪∶已经10点15了,本.
Maggie: It is ten fifteen, Ben.
本∶难怪我觉得今天晚上的时间特别长呢.
Ben: Well that's why the night seemed to drag on and on.
麦琪∶我说站住,我想要知道事实.
Maggie: I said, freeze, Mr.And I want the truth.
本∶哦,妈妈,爸爸,对不起,我想你们不会还没有睡.
Ben: Oh, Mom, Dad, I'm sorry; I didn't think you'd still be awake.
麦琪∶哦,你认为熬夜到晚上10点是很难的吗?
Maggie: Oh, you think it's tough to stay up past ten!
本∶总是这样的.
Ben: It always has been.
杰森∶所以,你就以为你可以溜进来,没有人会知道,对吗?
Jason: So, you just figured you'd just sneak in; nobody'd be the wiser, huh?
本∶重要的难道不是我安全到家了吗?
Ben: Isn't the important thing here, that I'm home safe?
麦琪∶谁说你安全了?
Maggie: Who says you're safe?
杰森∶本,
Jason: Ben, Ben, Ben,
本,本,
don't you think your mother and I are gonna get just a little tired of
你难道不认为你妈妈和我对一次又一次地这样的谈话有点厌卷了吗?
having this conversation over and over again?
本∶那想想我的感受.
Ben: Well, then imagine how I feel.
麦琪∶本,我心情不好,不要把你自己当万事通.
Maggie: Ben, can the wise-guy stuff, I am in no mood.
本∶那么或许我们应该早晨再来谈论这个...
Ben: Well then maybe we should talk about this in the morning...
等你们精神饱满后.
when you're fresh.
麦琪∶我现在就很精神饱满.你已经长大了,必须学会听话了.现在你还有什么要为你自己辩护的吗...最好不要是任何的瞎编的话.
Maggie: I am plenty fresh.Now Ben, this is getting old, you have got to learn to listen.Now, what do you have to say for yourself...and it better not be any back-talk.
本∶恩....
Ben: Well...
麦琪∶也不要跟我说抱歉.
Maggie: And don't tell me you're sorry.
麦琪∶妈妈...
Ben: Mom...
麦琪∶我在等!
Maggie: I'm waiting!
杰森∶麦琪..
Jason: Maggie...
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森∶你为何不和我到厨房说句话?
Jason: why don't you and I have a word in the kitchen?
麦琪∶啊,杰森,我很忙.
Maggie: Ah, Jason, I am busy here.
杰森∶麦琪,厨房!
Jason: Maggie, the kitchen!
麦琪∶为什么?
Maggie: Why?
杰森∶因为我不想要本看见我们吵架!
Jason: Because I don't want Ben to see us arguing!
麦琪∶本,如果在我们回来前,你动一下,或者是想动一下的的话,我,我一定会作出难以置信的举动!杰森,你要说什么?什么?我马上就要把事情摆平了.我是说,他应该知道我能解决事情,我们已经提前一步了!
Maggie: Ben, if you move, or even think of moving before we get back, I'll...I'll do something incredible!What is it Jason?What?I was just on a roll out there.I mean, he's gotta know that we can keep up with me, that we're one step ahead!
杰森∶麦琪!孩子只不过晚回来了15分钟.
Jason: Aw, Maggie, come on!The kid was just fifteen minutes late.
麦琪∶哦,只是 15分钟!只是15分钟!接下来他就会迟到115分钟...然后就会整晚呆在外面,接着就与一群惯犯呆在一起,最后你知道是什么吗,会要躲藏在教廷大使馆!
Maggie: Oh, just fifteen minutes late!Just fifteen minutes late!Well the next thing you know, he's a hundred and fifteen minutes late...and then he stays out all night, and then he falls into group of hardened criminals and the next thing you know, he's hiding out at the Vatican embassy!
杰森∶宝贝!
Jason: Sweetheart!
麦琪∶哦,你认为我又不可理喻了,不是吗?
Maggie: Oh, you think I'm being irrational, don't you?
杰森∶我认为...
Jason: Well, I...
麦琪∶哈,你不是吗?
Maggie: Ha!Don't you?Huh?
杰森∶我有权保持沉默.
Jason: I have the right to remain silent.
麦琪∶哦,我不可理喻.
Maggie: Oh, I am being irrational.
杰森∶宝贝儿,你累了.
Jason: Honey, you're tired.
麦琪∶哦,你想看我累的时候?等到克莉丝长大的时候吧.
Maggie: Oh, you wanna see tired?Wait till Chrissy's a teenager.
杰森∶我们不是说好要一起慢慢的变老的吗?
Jason: Oh, well didn't you and I always say that we wanted to grow old together?
麦琪∶是的,你知道为什么你还这么有理性吗,因为你比我小一岁.
Maggie: Yeah.You're only being rational because you're a year younger than me.
杰森∶:13个月.我们没有多少好日子剩下了.
Jason: Thirteen months.Come on!We got a couple of good years left.
你为何不在你有能力的时候去照顾克莉丝呢?
Why don't you go and take care of Chrissy while you still can.
麦琪∶克莉丝,我来了!妈咪来了!
Maggie: Coming Chrissy!Mommy's coming!
开萝尔∶妈妈,克莉丝在哭.
Carol: Mom, Chrissy's crying.
麦琪∶谢谢,开萝尔.
Maggie: Thank you, Carol.
开萝尔∶妈妈,你看上去有点疲惫.
Carol: Mom, you look tired.
麦琪∶孩子们让我累成这样的.
Maggie: Well, kids can take a lot out of you.
开萝尔∶这就是我打算在我年轻的时候生小孩的原因.
Carol: That's why I intend to have my children when I'm young.
麦琪∶哦,好了宝贝,妈咪在这里.妈咪在这里!你想妈妈摇摇吗?
Maggie: Oh, it's OK sweetheart, Mommy's here.Mommy's here!You wanna rock a little bit
克莉丝∶是.
Chrissy: Yeah.
麦琪∶是的!
Maggie: Yeah!
克莉丝∶是.
Chrissy: Yeah.
麦琪∶真好.你真乖.不要说我坐在这个椅子里很好.
Maggie: Yeah.You're such a good girl.Just don't say I look good in this chair.
没错,你是我的小天使.
Yeah, you're my little angel, aren't you sweetheart?Hmm.
恩,看在大家的份上,请不要改变.
For everybody's sake please stay that way.
你可能还没学数学,克莉丝,
You probably haven't done the math, Chrissy, but by the time you're eighteen,
想想等你18岁的时候,我差不多要...要...
I'm gonna be...Oh, I'm gonna be...
(麦琪的梦)
(Maggie's dream)
麦琪∶我们抓住你了,克莉丝西维尔!
Maggie: We caught you this time, Chrissy Seaver!
杰森∶我们真是在变老.
Jason: This is getting really old, young lady.
克莉丝∶说说看.
Chrissy: Tell me about it.
麦琪∶克莉丝西维尔,你去哪里了,
Maggie: Chrissy Seaver, where have you been,
我们很担心你.
we have been worried sick about you.
克莉丝∶妈妈,才10点半.
Chrissy: Mom, it's only ten thirty.
杰森∶你已经出去了3天了.
Jason: You've been gone three days.
克莉丝∶难怪这些衣服闻起来不好呢.
Chrissy: No wonder these clothes kind of smell.
麦琪∶小姐,你犯了大错,我也没情绪跟你兜来兜去的.
Maggie: Young lady, you are in big trouble and I am in no mood to fool around.
杰森∶我们已经好久没有了.
Jason: We haven't been in years.
麦琪∶杰森,我们在处理女儿的事情.
Maggie: Jason, we are dealing with our daughter.
杰森∶对.
Jason: Right.
麦琪∶你不知道我们会担心你?
Maggie: Don't you know we worry about you?
克莉丝∶重要的难道不是我安全到家了吗?
Chrissy: Mom!Isn't the important thing that I'm home, safe?
杰森∶我不知道,她说的不错,麦琪.
Jason: I don't know, she has a point Maggie.
麦琪∶没有!你到底去什么地方了?
Maggie: The heck she does!Where have you been?
克莉丝∶外面.
Chrissy: Out.
麦琪∶做什么?与谁一起?
Maggie: Doing what?With who?
克莉丝∶妈妈,我想要怎么生活就怎么生活,与其他人无关.
Chrissy: Mom, it's nobody's business what I do with my life and my body.
麦琪∶天啊.
Maggie: Oh, my God.
克莉丝∶对不起我让你不开心了...给,我给你找回了一些东西.
Chrissy: Look, I'm sorry I upset you...here, I bought you back something.
杰森∶哦,我的皮夹,谢谢克莉丝.
Jason: Oh, my wallet, thanks Chrissy.
克莉丝∶爸爸,
Chrissy: And Dad, I think a well-respected psychiatrist like yourself
我觉得像你这样一个受人尊敬的心理学家,信用卡的透支额应该更高一点才行,
should have much higher spending limits on his credit cards.
你让我觉得失望.
you're letting my down.
杰森∶对不起,克莉丝.我早晨就会给他们打电话.
Jason: I'm sorry, Chrissy.I'll make a call in the morning.
麦琪∶哦,杰森!她正在诱骗我们.不要让她得逞.
Maggie: Oh, Jason!She's conning us again.Don't let her do it.
杰森∶你说得对.克莉丝,你必须...凑合着用这些信用卡,我不会增加任何的透支额度.
Jason: You're right.Chrissy, you're just gonna have to...make do with these credit cards the way they are.
麦琪∶哦,杰森!她又骗了我们.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, she conned us again.
克莉丝∶妈妈,难道我关心你们也有罪吗?
Chrissy: Mom, is it a crime that I care about you?
难道我爱你们就是骗子了吗?
Is it a con that I love you?
这些就是我的感觉,有的时候我真的说不上来.
Cause that's how I feel, even sometimes when I don't know how to say it.
麦琪∶哦,克莉丝,只是...
Maggie: Oh, Chrissy, it's just that...
克莉丝∶我明白.你们都是为了我好.
Chrissy: I know.You have your rules for my own good.
麦琪∶说对了.
Maggie: Exactly.
克莉丝∶那样,我就可以长成一个好人.
Chrissy: So, that I can grow into a good person.
麦琪∶是.
Maggie: Yes.
克莉丝∶一快乐的人.
Chrissy: A happy person.
麦琪∶是.
Maggie: Yes.
克莉丝∶但是,当我不得不遵循你们的规则时,我觉得很不开心.
Chrissy: You know, it makes me unhappy when I have to follow your rules.
麦琪∶哦,杰森,我们把她弄哭了.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, look, we've made her cry.
杰森∶对不起,宝贝.
Jason: I'm sorry, sweetheart.
克莉丝∶但是刚才你们还想质问我!
Chrissy: But now you're gonna ground me!
麦琪∶哦,我们没有,杰森,是吗?
Maggie: Oh, no we aren't, are we Jason?
杰森∶对,没有!
Jason: No, siry!
克莉丝∶但是不管怎样,因为我迟到了几天,你们总是要惩罚我的.
Chrissy: But somehow you're gonna punish me for coming in just a few days late.
杰森∶对,对你的处罚就是你自己好好想想你自己做过的事情,
Jason: Yes, and your punishment will be...
以及错在哪里.
think about what you have done and why it's wrong.
克莉丝∶好.没问题.既然问题解决了,那我就要去找点东西吃了.你们是最好的父母.
Chrissy: OK.Done.Well, now that that's settled I'm gonna get something to eat.You guys are the best.
麦琪∶哦,杰森,杰森.她又骗了我们.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, Jason, she's done it again.
杰森∶她做什么了?
Jason: She did what?
麦琪∶她骗的我们无法对她进行惩罚了!
Maggie: She conned us out of punishing her!
杰森∶哦,没错,她是个聪明的孩子,不是吗?虽然经常逃课但是却仍然是全优学生.
Jason: Oh, yeah, she's a smart one, isn't she?Well, she cuts classes and gets straight A's.
麦琪∶恩,她有迈克的灵魂和开萝尔的头脑.
Maggie: Yeah, she's got Mike's soul and Carol's brain.
克莉丝∶嘿!没有食物了!!
Chrissy: Hey!There's no food in here!!
麦琪∶还有本的胃口.杰森,
Maggie: And Ben's appetite.
我们不能再逼着她去改变这些习性了.
Jason, we can't keep letting her get away with this behaviour.
杰森∶哦,想想我们老了后会是怎么样.
Jason: Oh, think about what it's gonna be like when we're old.
麦琪∶杰森,
Maggie: Jason, we are old.
我们已经老了.只是小13个月并不意味着很大一回事吧?
Being thirteen months younger doesn't amount to a hill of beans now, does it,
只吃得动软食物的先生?
Mr.soft food only?
杰森∶我要和那个女孩谈话,麦琪.
Jason: I'm gonna talk to that girl, Maggie.
麦琪∶杰森;我..
Maggie: Jason, I...
杰森∶对,我知道你要说,她不会理会大道理的...
Jason: Yeah, I know what you're gonna say, that she won't listen to reason...
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森∶但是难道我冗长的讨论没有影响到迈克,
Jason: But didn't my long-winded discussions make a difference with Mike
开萝尔和本吗?
and Carol and...Ben?
麦琪∶没有.
Maggie: No.
杰森∶没有!事情总是有第一次的,麦琪.克莉丝又再做什么?
Jason: No!Well there's always a first time, Maggie.What did Chrissy do again?
麦琪∶我跟你一起.
Maggie: I'll come with you.
杰森∶不在那里.
Jason: Not there.
克莉丝∶在这里.
Chrissy: Na.Yes.
杰森∶克莉丝请坐,我们不得不谈谈.你会怎么样叫你妈妈?
Jason: Chrissy have a seat, we have to talk.What'd you call your mother?
克莉丝∶爸爸,你想要对我说关于什么?
Chrissy: Dad, what do you wanna talk to me about?
杰森∶我想要谈论..
Jason: I wanna talk about...
麦琪∶关于离开3天...
Maggie: About being gone for three days.
杰森∶关于离开3天...
Jason: About being gone for three days.
麦琪∶天啊,我们变成里根了!
Maggie: My God, we've become the Ragins!
克莉丝∶我不知道到底有什么大不了.这好像也不是我第一次失踪吧.
Chrissy: You know, I don't know what the big deal is?It's not like it's the first time I've disappeared.
杰森∶说对了.
Jason: Exactly.
克莉丝∶爸爸,又要进行责任说教了吗?
Chrissy: Dad, please, is this gonna be the responsibility lecture?
杰森∶我在2者之间作着痛苦的抉择...总有一天你会感谢我.
Jason: I'm torn between that one and the one that goes...err...
我知道你妈妈喜欢那个.
some day you'll thank me for this.I know your mother likes that.
我是说也许我可以做,是因为我有心情...
I mean I can do either because I'm in the mood...
麦琪∶随便说一个!
Maggie: Just pick one!
杰森∶好.克莉丝,克莉丝,克莉丝!
Jason: Right.Chrissy, Chrissy, Chrissy!
麦琪∶哦,杰森,我讨厌这部分.说正题.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, I hate this part.Just get to the point.
杰森∶克莉丝,克莉丝,克莉丝....我总不能从中间开始吧,麦琪!
Jason: Chrissy, Chrissy, Chrissy...I can't start in the middle, Maggie!
麦琪∶克莉丝,克莉丝,克莉丝,
Maggie: Chrissy, Chrissy, Chrissy,
你总是这样跑来跑去,让我担心的不行.
you're worrying me and your mother to death with all this running around.
所以你能不能不要再这样了,就从这刻开始.就从这里开始.
I want it to stop, and stop this minute, young lady.Go from there.
杰森∶以后..
Jason: And in the future...
克莉丝∶将来,我要你答应我,
Chrissy: And in the future,
将决不再重复这些习性,
I want you to promise me that you'll never repeat this behaviour again.
不是为了你妈妈和我,而是为了你自己.
Do it for yourself, if not for your mother and me.
杰森∶我保证.
Jason: I promise.
麦琪∶不是你,是她.
Maggie: Not you, her.
克莉丝∶嘿;吉姆,发生什么啦?
Chrissy: Hey, Jim, what's up?
吉姆∶我必须检查一下刹车.
Jim: I gotta get those breaks checked.
克莉丝∶妈妈,爸爸,见见我的未婚夫,吉姆.
Chrissy: Mom, Dad, I want you to meet my fianc?Jim.
吉姆∶西维尔夫人,西维尔医生!
Jim: Mrs.Seaver, Dr.Seaver!
麦琪∶哦,杰森,你听见了吗?
Maggie: Oh, Jason, did you hear that?
杰森∶是,西维尔医生.我喜欢这个男孩.
Jason: Yeah, Doctor Seaver.I like this boy.
麦琪∶不,杰森,未婚夫?
Maggie: No, Jason, fianc?
杰森∶未婚夫?
Jason: Fianc?
麦琪∶是的,有点行动.
Maggie: Yes, do something.
杰森∶香肠?
Jason: Sausage?
麦琪∶克莉丝,克莉丝,你是说你爱这个...这个...
Maggie: Chrissy, Chrissy, look, do you mean to tell me that you love this...this
吉姆∶越野爱好者?
Jim: Off road hobbyist?
克莉丝∶是,妈妈,我非常爱他.
Chrissy: Yes, Mom, I love him very much.
吉姆∶西维尔医生和太太,我也是个很坦白的人,所以我要说的是,要不是因为她有那么美妙的身体,我才不会试着去爱你们的女儿.克莉丝,走吧,我们聚会要迟到了.
Jim: And Doctor and Mrs.Seaver, I'm an honest kind of guy, so I wanna tell you I don't really love your daughter, but with a body like that I'm gonna learn to.Come on Chrissy, hop on, we're gonna be late for the party.
克莉丝∶好了,我准备好了.
Chrissy: OK, I'm ready.
吉姆∶这也是我喜欢你的一点.
Jim: That's what I like about you.
麦琪∶哦,什么聚会?
Maggie: Oh, what party?
吉姆∶在你们的起居室那个.
Jim: The one in your living room.
麦琪∶哦,杰森,杰森,我们走!
Maggie: Oh, Jason, Jason, let's go!
杰森∶麦琪,我们没有被邀请.
Jason: Maggie, we're not invited.
麦琪∶杰森!
Maggie: Jason!
杰森∶好吧,我们走!也许我应该试试那套老的关于做你自己的的说教,你知道,迈克从来都不愿意听的.
Jason: Alright let's go Maggie, come on!Maybe I'll try the old, be your self lecture, you know, the one Mike never listened to?
麦琪∶没有说教!让我来管..杰森.杰森,你失去机会了.从我们要送克莉丝到托儿所的第一天,而你却想看愚蠢的篮球比赛时.
Maggie: No more lectures!I'm taking over...Jason.Jason, you've lost it.I saw this coming from the day we took Chrissy to play school and you wanted to watch that stupid basketball game.
杰森∶麦琪,你总是热心于研究我做父母的技巧.
Jason: Maggie, you always had such enthusiasm for my skills as a parent.
麦琪∶是,很早以前就开始了.
Maggie: Yes, a long time ago.
但是,坦白说,
But frankly Jason, and I'll just say it,
杰森,我也只能说,一直以来我都在伪装我的热情.
I've been faking my enthusiasm for years.
杰森,你有没有听进去一个我所说的?
Jason, have you heard a word I've said?
杰森∶尼克斯赢了那场比赛,还是我的记忆错误?
Jason: Did the Knicks win that game, or is my memory faulty?
麦琪∶哦,天啊,我简直不能相信!
Maggie: Oh, my God, I can't believe this!
杰森∶吉姆居然可以摇动他的身体.
Jason: Yeah, that Jim can really shake his booty.
麦琪∶所有人都给我住口,听着!
Maggie: Everyone shut up and listen now!
聚会的人∶哇!
Partiers: Wow!
麦琪∶我不是要说教!我也不是精神变态的唠叨!
Maggie: I'm not going to lecture!I'm not going to psycho babble!
我只是想说这是我的房子,是我的女儿,
I am just going to say that this is my home and this is my daughter
所以,我不会让这个聚会继续在这里多开一分钟.所有人,
and I am not going to have this party continue in my house for one more
马上给我滚出去!不是你杰森.
minute.Now, everybody out, now!Not you Jason.
吉姆∶别这样!
Jim: Come on!
克莉丝∶聪明点,妈妈.你已经失去了.
Chrissy: Wise up, Mom.You've lost it.
麦琪∶哦,杰森.她说的对.我已经失去了它.结束了.你在这里做什么?
Maggie: Oh, Jason, she's right.I have lost it.It's all over.What are you doing here?
迈克∶处理这个.打扰一下.唷!所有人,请注意!在下面第3个房间里,还有一个更酷的聚会呢,有实况音乐和活的动物!你们最好快去!克莉丝,你不想换一个吗?
Mike: Handling this.Excuse me.Yo!Everybody, can I have your attention please!There is a much cooler party, happening only three houses down, with live music and live animals!You better hurry!Chrissy, don't you take another step!
克莉丝∶但是,吉姆!
Chrissy: But, Jim!
吉姆∶哦,你没有听见他的话吗,宝贝!活的动物!
Jim: Oh, you heard him, babe!Live animals!
克莉丝∶迈克,你知道你在做什么吗?
Chrissy: Mike, what in the hell do you think you're doing?
迈克∶首先我要告诉再也,永远也不要让我听到你在我们的父母面前说这些词!
Mike: Well, first of all I am telling you to never,
以示尊敬!
ever let me hear you use that language in front of our parents!Show respect!
克莉丝∶但是迈克!
Chrissy: But Mikey!
迈克∶不要,迈克,我!
Mike: Don't, Mikey, me!And you can turn off the phony tears.
擦干你那假模假样的眼泪.克莉丝,
Chrissy, we are talking about responsibility here.
我们现在谈论的是责任.我现在要告诉你一些事情,在你以后你会感谢我的.
Now I'm gonna tell you something, and someday you'll thank me for this.
杰森∶我跟他说的.
Jason: I gave him that one.
迈克∶这是真正的你吗?一个叛逆的,宠坏的让父母伤心的小坏蛋!克莉丝,克莉丝,克莉丝,做你自己.
Mike: Is this who you really are?A bratty, spoilt little pain in the rear.Chrissy, Chrissy, Chrissy ,be yourself.
杰森∶也是我跟他说的.
Jason: Gave him that one too.
迈克∶他们俩是世界是最棒的父母.
Mike: And these two people are the best darn parents in the world.
你难道不知道去珍惜吗?
But do you appreciate it?No.
不知道的,我花了15年的时间终于弄明白他们跟我说的每一句话都是对的,
Let me share something with you; you know,
而我自己的想法完全是错误的.
it took me fifteen years to figure out that everything they told me was right.
马上给我上楼去,
And everything I thought, was completely wrong.Now grow up!
完成你的家庭作业!
Go upstairs and get started on your homework.
克莉丝∶但是我一直都是全优学生.
Chrissy: But I get straight A's.
迈克∶那个就是你能做到的?
Mike: Is that the best you can do?
克莉丝∶不是,对不起.
Chrissy: No.I'm sorry.
麦琪∶迈克,因此这些年来,你一直都有听进去我们的话!
Maggie: Mike, so you have been listening to us all these years!
杰森∶我们!我可没有听见他引用你的一句话,麦琪.
Jason: Us!I didn't hear him quoting you there, Maggie.
迈克∶恩,当我知道你们有麻烦时,
Mike: Well, when I heard you two were in trouble,
我马上离开办公室,以最快的速度赶过来.
I left the office and got here as quick as I could.
麦琪∶哦,迈克,
Maggie: Oh, Mike, I've been meaning to ask you;
我一直都想问你,你实际上做的是什么?
what is it that you actually do?
迈克∶我自己也不知道.我很成功.
Mike: Well, I don't really know.I'm very successful.
麦琪∶杰森,我们的儿子很成功的.
Maggie: Jason, our son is successful.
开萝尔∶妈妈,爸爸!
Carol: Mom, Dad!When my parents need me, the supreme court can wait.
当我的父母需要我,最高法院也可以等.一切都好了吗?
Is everything alright?
麦琪∶哦,一切都很好...因为迈克.
Maggie: Oh, everything's wonderful...because of Mike.
本∶我早就应该知道的.不应该那么早就下班结果却什么也帮不上.
Ben: I should've known.I left work early for nothing.
杰森∶本,你又在干什么?
Jason: Ben, what is it you do again?
本∶我为迈克工作.
Ben: I work for Mike.
迈克∶就像爸爸经常说的,我们做什么不重要,因为我们是一家人,我们永远都在一起,我们爱你们!否则我们为什么还要住在这个房子里?
Mike: As Dad said over and over, it doesn't really matter what we do because we're family, we rally together and we love you guys!Why else would we all still be living in this house?
麦琪∶杰森,梦想终于实现了.
Maggie: Jason, this is like a dream come true.
杰森∶哦,如果是梦,我就不想把你吵醒,麦琪.
Jason: Oh, if it's a dream, I don't want to wake up, Maggie.
麦琪∶什么?
Maggie: What?
杰森∶醒醒,麦琪.醒醒,麦琪.
Jason: Wake up, Maggie.Wake up, Maggie.
杰森∶醒醒,麦琪.醒醒,麦琪.麦琪,醒醒.醒醒,麦琪.
Jason: Wake up, Maggie.Wake up, Maggie.Maggie, wake up.Wake up, Maggie.
麦琪∶杰森....杰森,你是这么年轻.
Maggie: Jas...Jason, you're so young.
杰森∶谢谢你.
Jason: Thank you.
麦琪∶哦,并且克莉丝还是一个婴孩.
Maggie: Oh, and Chrissy's still a baby.
.杰森∶是.
Jason: Yep
麦琪∶哦,我也还很年轻..
Maggie: Oh, and...oh and I'm young too
杰森∶发生什么事了?
Jason: Mmm.What's all this about?
麦琪∶哦,杰森,
Maggie: Oh, Jason, we're gonna be OK.We're good parents, we're not losing it!
一切都会好的.我们是好父母,
We get through to our kids; it doesn't always seem like it, but we do.
我们不会失去它!我们明白我们的孩子们;所有的事情并不是像表面上的那样.
Even your dumb lectures sink in!
你的愚蠢的说教也被听进去了!亲爱的,就算我们变老也没有关系,
Honey, it's OK if we get old, I mean its tough, but when we do,
虽然会比较难过,但是我们可以依靠我们的孩子,
we can count on our kids and I love you and I wanna grow old with
我爱你,我只想和你一起变老.
you.
杰森∶愚蠢的说教!等一下!
Jason: Dumb lectures!Wait a minute!
这些车为什么都停在我们的车道上.
What are all those cars doing pulling into our drive-way.
迈克有差不多30个孩子去了他的地方.
Mike's got about thirty kids going up to his place.
麦琪,我要阻止它.
Maggie, I'm gonna put a stop to this.
麦琪∶哦,杰森,不要对他太严格.在我们丧失能力后,我们需要他来帮我们化险为夷.
Maggie: Oh, Jason, don't be too tough on him.We're gonna need him to save the day, after we've lost it.
杰森∶噢呼.
Jason: Uh hu.
麦琪∶哦,亲爱的,还有一件事情是,我从来都没有假装我对你的热情.
Maggie: Oh, and honey, one more thing; I have never, ever faked my enthusiasm for you.
杰森∶呵呵,对一个男人来说,知道这件事情很开心.
麦琪∶哦,克莉丝,是的!是的!是的!这是什么?不.
00:21:49,500
Jason: It's a good thing for a guy to know. Maggie: Oh, Chrissy, yes!Yes!Yes!What's this?No.